<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pipelines on Variant Tools</title>
    <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pipelines on Variant Tools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Calling variants using BWA and GATK best practice pipeline Usage This pipeline is deprecated because version 2.3 of the GATK resource bundle is no longer available.
% vtools show pipeline bwa_gatk_hg19 A pipeline to align raw reads from fastq or BAW/SAM files using BWA and GATK best practice. It uses hg19 of human reference genome and assumes paired-end reads in plain text and compressed formats. Available pipelines: align, call Pipeline &amp;quot;align&amp;quot;: Align raw reads from input files using bwa, gatk, and picard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/customizedpipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/customizedpipeline/</guid>
      <description>Specification of a variant tools pipeline This page describes the new pipeline format (version 1.1 and later). Please refer to Format1_0? if you are editing a pipeline specification file for variant tools 2.7 and earlier..
Intxroduction Variant Tools uses pipeline specification files to define pipelines. A pipeline specification file can define multiple pipelines. It can be stored locally or online in the variant tools repository (or a local repository maintained by your system adminstrator).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/format10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/format10/</guid>
      <description>Specification of a variant tools pipeline This page describes the original pipeline format (version 1.0). Please refer to New? if you are editing a new pipeline specification file for variant tools 2.7 and later.
1. Introduction Variant Tools uses pipeline specification files to define pipelines. A pipeline specification file can define multiple pipelines. It can be stored locally or online in the variant tools repository (or a local repository maintained by your system adminstrator).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>