<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pipelines on Variant Tools</title>
    <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pipelines on Variant Tools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/customizedpipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/customizedpipeline/</guid>
      <description>Specification of a variant tools pipeline 1. Introduction Variant Tools uses pipeline specification files to define pipelines. A pipeline specification file can define multiple pipelines. It can be stored locally or online in the variant tools repository (or a local repository maintained by your system adminstrator). You can use command
% vtools show pipelines  to get a list of all publicly available pipelines, and
% vtools show pipeline SPECFILE  to get the details of pipelines defined in SPECFILE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized10</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/format10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/format10/</guid>
      <description>Specification of a variant tools pipeline This page describes the original pipeline format (version 1.0). Please refer to New if you are editing a new pipeline specification file for variant tools 2.7 and later.
1. Introduction Variant Tools uses pipeline specification files to define pipelines. A pipeline specification file can define multiple pipelines. It can be stored locally or online in the variant tools repository (or a local repository maintained by your system adminstrator).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>