<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Single gene on Variant Tools</title>
    <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Single gene on Variant Tools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>C-alpha test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/c_alpha-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/c_alpha-test/</guid>
      <description>C-alpha Test for Protective Variants 1. Introduction This implements the {$C(\alpha)$} test (Neale et al 2011) for disease traits, to test for the hypothesis of rare variants disease association under the particular assumption that rare variants observed in cases and controls is a mixture of phenotypically deleterious, protective and neutral variants. Instead of using a cumulative dosage (or &amp;ldquo;burden&amp;rdquo;) based summary statistic over a gene region, it directly contrasts the observed and expected distribution of minor alleles in cases and controls at each locus as an evidence of &amp;ldquo;unusual distribution&amp;rdquo;, and combine evidences from multiple loci (whether it be an evidence of protective or deleterious) to formulate the \(C(\alpha)\) statistic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KBAC test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/kbac-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/kbac-test/</guid>
      <description>Kernel Based Adaptive Clustering Method 1. Introduction This is implementation for the KBAC statistic in (Liu and Leal 2010). It carries out case-control association testing for rare variants for whole exome association studies. Briefly, consider a gene of length n which harbors m rare variants. Genotype on the m variant sites &amp;amp; the disease status (case/control) are known for each individual. The program takes as input the m-site genotype and disease status (case/control) data files, and computes a p-value indicating the significance of association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBT test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/rbt-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/rbt-test/</guid>
      <description>Replication Based Test for Protective Variants 1. Introduction This is implementation for the replication base test in (Ionita-Laza et al 2011). The key of this method is replication, i.e., in the two-sided test of RBT it computes evidences to reject each of the two hypothesis
 Deleterious rare variants are enriched in cases Protective rare variants are enriched in controls  The final statistic is based on the stronger of the two evidences, adjusted for multiple testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VT test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/vt-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/vt-test/</guid>
      <description>Variable Thresholds Test for Case Control Data Analysis 1. Introduction The variable thresholds method (VT, Price et al 2010) tests for association between phenotypic values (case control or quantitative traits) with individuals&amp;rsquo; genotype &amp;ldquo;score&amp;rdquo; subject to a variable MAF threshold. It assumes that there exists a fixed yet unknown MAF threshold on a given genetic region which is related to the cutoff for the causality of variants on that loci. In testing the association for the genetic region, for each possible MAF threshold a genotype score is computed based on given collapsing theme, and is tested for association between the phenotype of interest; the final MAF threshold is chosen such that the association signal is strongest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSS test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/wss-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single_gene/wss-test/</guid>
      <description>Weighted Sum Statistic via Rank Test 1. Introduction The method proposed by Madsen and Browning 2009 first introduced the idea of assigning &amp;ldquo;weights&amp;rdquo; to rare variants within a genetic region before they are collapsed. In this case the variants having higher weights will have more substantial contribution to the collapsed variant score. In the Madsen &amp;amp; Browning paper the &amp;ldquo;weights&amp;rdquo; are defined as \(\sqrt{n_iq_i(1-q_i)}\) with the assumption that the &amp;ldquo;rarer&amp;rdquo; the variant, the larger the risk effect it is to a phenotype.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>