<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentation on vatlab</title>
    <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentation on vatlab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://faculty.mdanderson.org/profiles/bo_peng.html&#34;&gt;Bo Peng, Ph.D. / MD Anderson Cancer Center&lt;/a&gt; All rights reserved</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Key concepts</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/keyconcepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/keyconcepts/</guid>
      <description>Key concepts Project variant tools is project based. All data need to be imported to the project to be analyzed. A variant tools project $name consists of a project file $name.proj, a genotype database $name_genotype.DB, and a log file $name.log. After a project is created, subsequent vtools calls will automatically load the project in the current directory. Working from outside of a project directory is not allowed.
(:toggleexample:) Let us create a sample project and import two datasets from the pilot phase of the 1000 genomes project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Tutorials These tutorials explain steps that are used to analyze real-world sequencing data. We will try to explain the steps in detail but command output are usually ignored for brevity and confidentiality reasons.
Quick Start Guide This is a 10-minute quick start guide using data from the 1000 genomes project. We encourage you to walk through this minimal real-world example to get a feel for the software and assess its helpfulness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/help/</guid>
      <description>Usage of variant tools commands Structure of commands vtools uses a subcommand system that is similar to svn. For example, command
% vtools select variant &#39;sift_score &amp;lt; 0.05&#39; -t table  consists of:
 command vtools subcommand select that specify operation, positional arguments variant that specifies a variant table and &#39;sift_score &amp;lt; 0.05&#39; that specify operant, which in this case are the variant table to select from, and condition by which the variants are selected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>