<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multivariate on Variant Tools</title>
    <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/joint_conditional/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multivariate on Variant Tools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/joint_conditional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>variable thresholds</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/joint_conditional/variable-thresholds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/joint_conditional/variable-thresholds/</guid>
      <description>Varible Thresholds Methods for Disease and Quantitative Traits 1. Introduction This implements the variable thresholds version of aggregation methods. Similar to the VT method, the VariableThresholdsBt and VariableThresholdsQt tests use a variable thresholds definition for the rare variants being considered such that multiple test statistics are calculated for an aggregation unit. The final statistic is taken as the one that gives the best result. Type I error is controlled due to the use of permutation testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SKAT test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/joint_conditional/skat-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/joint_conditional/skat-test/</guid>
      <description>SNP-set (Sequence) Kernel Association Test Method 1. Details 1.1 Command interface vtools show test SKAT Name: SKAT Description: SKAT (Wu et al 2011) wrapper of its original R implementation usage: vtools associate --method SKAT [-h] [--name NAME] [-k {linear,linear.weighted,IBS,IBS.weighted,quadratic,2wayIX}] [--beta_param BETA_PARAM BETA_PARAM] [-m {davies,liu,liu.mod,optimal}] [-i {fixed,random}] [--logistic_weights PARAM PARAM] [-r [CORR [CORR ...]]] [--missing_cutoff MISSING_CUTOFF] [--resampling N] [--small_sample] [--resampling_kurtosis N] {quantitative,disease} SNP-set (Sequence) Kernel Association Test (Wu et al 2011). This is a wrapper for the R package &amp;quot;SKAT&amp;quot; implemented &amp;amp; maintained by Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetaSKAT</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/joint_conditional/metaskat-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/joint_conditional/metaskat-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Association Analysis with the Meta SKAT R Program The R extension for RTest is available HERE. For details on the format of this script please refer to the RTest method documentation.
1. Example We analyze association with a binary trait named X6 conditioning on 3 covariates X8, X9, X10. Group information is provided by race. For each testing group, data is first cleaned by removing samples missing greater than 50% calls, then by removing variants missing 50% calls.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>