<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Variant Tools</title>
    <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Variant Tools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>All recent changes</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/administration/allrecent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/administration/allrecent/</guid>
      <description>Annotation.New? &amp;hellip; March 06, 2018, at 09:45 PM by ?: VtoolsReport.InbreedingCoefficient? &amp;hellip; March 06, 2018, at 09:31 PM by ?: Main.Concepts? &amp;hellip; March 06, 2018, at 06:10 PM by ?: Main.Installation? &amp;hellip; March 06, 2018, at 03:31 AM by ?: Main.HomePage &amp;hellip; March 04, 2018, at 04:52 AM by ?: Vtools.Show? &amp;hellip; September 20, 2017, at 09:16 PM by ?: Annotation.DbSNP? &amp;hellip; September 05, 2017, at 07:19 PM by Man Chong Leong?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSMIC</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/cosmic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/cosmic/</guid>
      <description>Catalogue of Somatic Mutations in Cancer COSMIC (Catalogue of Somatic Mutations in Cancer) is a data resource that is designed to store and display somatic mutation information and related details and contains information relating to human cancers. Data in COSMIC is curated from known Cancer Genes Literature and Systematic Screens. COSMIC data is freely downloadable in many formats on the project&amp;rsquo;s FTP site: ftp://ftp.sanger.ac.uk/pub/CGP/cosmic.
If you use COSMIC annotations, please credit the project with the following acknowledgement:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChangeLog</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/development/changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/development/changelog/</guid>
      <description>Change Log of variant tools Version 2.7.0 (Released on Jan 20, 2016) MAJOR NEW FEATURES:
 Normalize variants using reference sequence information before importing variants. New file format for spec file of variant pipeline tools. Support arbitrary reference genome.  BUG FIXES:
 Fix importing wildtype genotypes in some cases.  Version 2.6.1 (Released on Jan 15, 2015)  Fix a few small bugs introduced in 2.6.0. Fix compatibility issues with Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collapsing methods</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/collapsing-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/collapsing-methods/</guid>
      <description>Collapsing Methods for Disease and Quantitative Traits Introduction This is implementation of the fixed threshold collapsing methods for both disease and quantitative traits. Collapsing method for rare variants treats a genetic region as a test unit; based on observed genotype it assigns a numeric coding to the region {$X$}:{$$X = I_(0,N)(\sum_i^N X_i)$$} i.e., the observed genotype will be coded as {$1$} if there exists at least one mutation, and {$0$} otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fisher exact test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-variant-analysis/fisher-exact-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-variant-analysis/fisher-exact-test/</guid>
      <description>Fisher&amp;rsquo;s Exact Test for Single Variant Analysis Introduction Genetic association studies of common variants in case control samples usually compare directly the differences in frequencies of an allele or genotype between case and control populations, with the assumption that a significant difference in frequencies is indication to association between the locus and increase risk of disease. Many statistical tests for binomial or multinomial proportions can be used for such analysis, including Fisher&amp;rsquo;s exact test, {$\chi^2$} test and Cochran-Armitage Trend Test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group stat&amp;Write</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/basic-data-statistics/group-statwrite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/basic-data-statistics/group-statwrite/</guid>
      <description>Basic Statistics for Association Testing Units Introduction GroupStat and GroupWrite are &amp;ldquo;ancillary&amp;rdquo; features for the collection of VAT association tests. Instead of carrying out association analysis, GroupStat reports summary statistics of an association test unit such as total allele counts, total variant counts, number of samples, etc., while GroupWrite output genotype and phenotype information (into zipped bundles) in the format compatible with the SCORE-Seq software such that the data can be closely examined or manipulated using other software tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illumina</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/misc/illumina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/misc/illumina/</guid>
      <description> Expanded exome regions of Nextera Rapid Capture Exome and Expanded Exome Enrichment Kits from Illumina.
Usage % vtools show annotation Illumina_NRCE Annotation database Illumina_NRCE (version 20130307) Description: This annotation database contains expanded exome targeted regions covered by the Nextera Rapid Capture Expanded platform from illumina. Database type: range Reference genome hg19: Chromosome, Start, End Name Name of region Chromosome Start Transcription start position End Transcription end position  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Init</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/init/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/init/</guid>
      <description>Create a new project 1. Usage % vtools init -h usage: vtools init [-h] [-f] [--parent DIR_or_SNAPSHOT] [--variants [TABLE]] [--samples [COND [COND ...]]] [--genotypes [COND [COND ...]]] [--children DIR_OR_SNAPSHOT [DIR_OR_SNAPSHOT ...]] [-v {0,1,2}] project Create a new project in the current directory. This command will fail if another project already exists in this directory, unless option &#39;--force&#39; is used to remove the existing project. positional arguments: project Name of a new project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Variant annotation using variant tools Annotation Functions of Variant tools Variant, info fields, and annotation fields Variants in a variant tools project are stored in a master variant table after they are imported? from external data files. Multiple variant info fields could be added to this table to describe these variant. These fields could be imported from a file? when variants are imported, or updated? from files after variants are imported, calculated from samples as sample statistics, or derived from other variant info or annotation fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Variant Association Tools About Variant Association Tools (VAT), designed and developed by Gao Wang (Baylor College of Medicine), Dr. Bo Peng (the University of Texas, MD Anderson Cancer Center) and Dr. Suzanne Leal (Baylor College of Medicine), is a new developmental branch of variant tools expanding its scope from analyzing individual genomic variants to analyzing large sequence data (whole genome sequencing, whole exome sequencing) or exome genotyping arrays (exome chips) from population based genotype-phenotype association studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Single gene Association Tests for Single Gene and Case Control Phenotypes The application of next-generation sequencing methods to the discovery of disease causal genes has been successful in finding rare genetic mutations responsible for a number of Mendalian disorders. There is growing evidence that rare variants contribute to the etiology of complex traits and whole genome (or exome) squencing in large populations provides valuable resource for identifying such variants. Although it is believed that effect size of rare variants to complex diseases is usually higher compare to common variants, due to the low frequency of rare variants large sample size is required to detect the effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/simulation/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/simulation/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Variant Simulation Tools A presentation about variant simulation tools (Sep. 2014)
Variant Simulation Tools is still under development. Development (subversion) versions of Variant Tools and simuPOP are needed to use VST. Also, because of a lack of mature simulation models (only two examples in the submitted paper are available), users are strongly advised to contact me for the creation of any simulation model.
What is Variant Simulation Tools Variant Simulation Tools (VST) is a simulation tool for post-GWAS genetic epidemiological studies using whole-genome or whole-exome next-gen sequencing data, with an emphasis on user-friendliness and reproducibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Calling variants using BWA and GATK best practice pipeline Usage This pipeline is deprecated because version 2.3 of the GATK resource bundle is no longer available.
% vtools show pipeline bwa_gatk_hg19 A pipeline to align raw reads from fastq or BAW/SAM files using BWA and GATK best practice. It uses hg19 of human reference genome and assumes paired-end reads in plain text and compressed formats. Available pipelines: align, call Pipeline &amp;quot;align&amp;quot;: Align raw reads from input files using bwa, gatk, and picard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low complexity regions</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/regions/low-complexity-regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/regions/low-complexity-regions/</guid>
      <description> Low Complexity and RepetitiveRegions Low Complexity Regions </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peng2014_ex1</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/simulation/models/peng1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/simulation/models/peng1/</guid>
      <description>Simulations for the first example of Peng (2014) Genetic Epidemiology Usage $ vtools show simulation Peng2014_ex1 Simulations of DNA sequences in specified regions using different simulation methods, for the first example in paper &amp;quot;Reproducible Simulations of realistic samples for next-gen sequencing studies using Variant Simulation Tools&amp;quot;. The simulated populations are analyzed and discarded to save diskspace. Available simulation models: ms, neutral, resample, with_selection Model &amp;quot;ms&amp;quot;: This simulator calls ms to execute coalescent-based simulations, create a population with simulated dataset and run through the same statistical analysis as other pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QQ plot and Manhattan plot</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/view-association-result/qq-plot-and-manhattan-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/view-association-result/qq-plot-and-manhattan-plot/</guid>
      <description>Graphic Summary of Association Analysis Introduction vtools_report plot_association generates QQ plot and Manhattan plot of p-values from output of vtools associate command. The graphics are powered by the R package ggplot2. Fonts, color, page layout etc can be specified from the command interface, generating high quality and customized graphs.
Input data format vtools associate command typically generates two types of output: output of gene based association tests and single variant analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running R programs</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/create-your-test/running-r-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/create-your-test/running-r-programs/</guid>
      <description>A General Framework for Association Analysis Using R Programs Introduction A number of rare variant association methods as well as the flexible VAT ensemble algorithm makes it possible to conveniently evaluate variant associations via different statistical options. In addition to the existing association testing framework, variant association tools can talk to R via customized R programs prepared by users. Under this mechanism, users write up an R function that analyzes data of an association testing unit (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supported types of variants</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/keyconcepts/supportedtypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/keyconcepts/supportedtypes/</guid>
      <description>Supported types of variants How variants are imported and stored in variant tools variant tools import different types of variants as follows:
   Type Reference Alternative Imported Variant(s) Note     SNV A G A,G     TC TG C,G pos + 1   Deletion TC T C,- pos + 1    TCG TG C,- pos + 1    TCGC TC GC,- pos + 2, *    TC - or .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>avg_depth</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/avg_depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/avg_depth/</guid>
      <description>Average depth of coverage Ratio About vtools_report avg_depth This command report average depth of all variants, or variants divided by sample allele count.
Usage % vtools_report avg_depth -h usage: vtools_report avg_depth [-h] -n NUM_FIELD -d DEPTH_FIELD [--group_by [GROUP_BY [GROUP_BY ...]]] [-v {0,1,2}] table Command &#39;vtools update table --from_stat &amp;quot;meanDP=avg(DP_geno)&amp;quot;&#39; calculates the average depth of variants across sample (e.g. average depth of three variants if the variant appears three times in the sample).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>basic</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/txt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/txt/</guid>
      <description>Importing variants from tab-delimited files Format description % vtools show format basic A basic variant import/export format that import variants with four tab- delimited columns (chr, pos, ref, alt), and export variants, optional variant info fields and genotypes. Columns: 1 Output variant info fields as one column 2 variant position, set --pos_adj to -1 to export variants in 0-based positions. 3 reference allele 4 alternative allele 5 genotype in numeric style Formatters are provided for fields: gt variant: chr Chromosome pos 1-based position, set --pos_adj to 1 if input position is 0 based.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bwa_gatk33_hg19</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/variant-calling/bwa_gatk33_hg19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/variant-calling/bwa_gatk33_hg19/</guid>
      <description>Variant calling using BWA and GATK best practice pipeline Usage % vtools show pipeline bwa_gatk33_hg19 A pipeline to align raw reads from fastq or BAM/SAM files using BWA and GATK best practice. It uses hg19 of human reference genome and assumes paired-end reads in plain text and compressed formats. Available pipelines: align Pipeline &amp;quot;align&amp;quot;: Align raw reads from input files using bwa, gatk, and picard. This pipeline accepts raw input files in plain text format, SAM/BAM format, and their compressed versions (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ccdsGene</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/ccdsgene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/ccdsgene/</guid>
      <description>This database contains high-confidence human gene annotations from the Consensus Coding Sequence (CCDS) project. It was constructed from the UCSC Genome Browser ccdsGene track. If you would like to annotate your variants to these genes, you can use the simpler ccdsGene database. If you would like to determine the exons that your variants are in, use the ccdsGene_exon database. See the available annotation fields for each database below.
ccdsGene % vtools show annotation ccdsGene -v2 Annotation database ccdsGene (version hg19_20130904) Description: High-confidence human gene annotations from the Consensus Coding Sequence (CCDS) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>import_vcf</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/import_vcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/import_vcf/</guid>
      <description>Import all variant and genotype fields from vcf files Usage % vtools show pipeline import_vcf This pipeline creates a customized .fmt file to import all variant and genotype info fields of input vcf files. Available pipelines: import_vcf Pipeline &amp;quot;import_vcf&amp;quot;: This pipeline creates a customized .fmt file by scanning the header of input vcf files and imports all variant and genotype info fields of the input files in VCF format. If an output file is specified (--output), it will be used to save the customized .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ref_sequence</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/ref_sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/ref_sequence/</guid>
      <description>Reference sequence around variant site Usage Function ref_sequence(chr, start, end) returns the reference sequence between start and end on chromosome chr of the reference genome (primary reference genome unless parameter --build is used to specify an alternative reference genome). If end is unspecified, ref_sequence(chr, pos) returns the reference allele at the specified location. This function is very useful in output the context of variants or select variants based on the contexts (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>report_progress</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/utilities/report_progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/utilities/report_progress/</guid>
      <description>Report the progress of the execution of pipelines ChangeLog  Dec 30, 2013: Initial release  Download Download report_progress, use
% python report_progress
or execute
% report_progress
directly after chmod +x report_progress.
Note: Python module matplotlib is required to execute this script.
Introduction variant tools records the progress of the execution of pipelines in log files. This script parses the log files, extract the starting end ending time of the execution of each step of the pipeline, and plots them in a resulting pdf file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregation methods</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/aggregation-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/aggregation-methods/</guid>
      <description>Aggregation Methods for Disease and Quantitative Traits Introduction This is implementation of the fixed threshold aggregation methods for disease and quantitative traits. Originally described in Morris and Zeggni 2010[^Andrew P. Morris and Eleftheria Zeggini (2010) An evaluation of statistical approaches to rare variant analysis in genetic association studies. Genetic Epidemiology doi:10.1002/gepi.20450. http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/gepi.20450^] and known as Gene- or Region-based Analysis of Variants of Intermediate and Low frequency (GRANVIL), the Aggregation method for rare variants codes observed genotype of a genetic region the count of minor alleles: {$$X = \sum_i^N X_i$$}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autolink</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/administration/autolink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/administration/autolink/</guid>
      <description>vtools -h|vtools/commands vtools init|vtools/init vtools import|vtools/import vtools export|vtools/export vtools update|vtools/update vtools phenotype|vtools/phenotype vtools liftover|vtools/liftover vtools show|vtools/show vtools subsample|vtools/subsample vtools remove|vtools/remove vtools merge|vtools/merge vtools use|vtools/use vtools output|vtools/output vtools select|vtools/select vtools admin|vtools/admin vtools exclude|vtools/exclude vtools execute|vtools/execute vtools compare|vtools/compare vtools associate|vtools/associate vtools_report -h|vtools/commands vtools_report trans_ratio|vtools_report/trans_ratio vtools_report avg_depth|vtools_report/avg_depth vtools_report variant_stat|vtools_report/variant_stat vtools_report discordance_rate|vtools_report/discordance_rate vtools_report inbreeding_coefficient|vtools_report/inbreeding_coefficient vtools_report sequence|vtools_report/sequence vtools_report plot_fields|vtools_report/plot_fields vtools_report plot_pheno_fields|vtools_report/plot_pheno_fields vtools_report plot_geno_fields|vtools_report/plot_geno_fields vtools_report plot_association|vtools_report/plot_association vtools_report meta_analysis|vtools_report/meta_analysis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMC test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/cmc-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/cmc-test/</guid>
      <description>Combined and Multivariate Collapsing Method for Rare Variants Introduction This is the Combined and Multivariate Collapsing (CMC, Li and Leal, 2008[^Bingshan Li and Suzanne M. Leal (2008) Methods for Detecting Associations with Rare Variants for Common Diseases: Application to Analysis of Sequence Data. The American Journal of Human Genetics doi:10.1016/j.ajhg.2008.06.024. http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0002929708004084^]) test for rare variants. CMC method considers all variants in a test unit (e.g., a gene). It &amp;ldquo;collapses&amp;rdquo; all rare variants in the gene region such that the region is coded &amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; if all loci are wildtype, and &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo; if any one locus has a minor allele.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized pipeline</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/customizedpipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/customizedpipeline/</guid>
      <description>Specification of a variant tools pipeline This page describes the new pipeline format (version 1.1 and later). Please refer to Format1_0? if you are editing a pipeline specification file for variant tools 2.7 and earlier..
Intxroduction Variant Tools uses pipeline specification files to define pipelines. A pipeline specification file can define multiple pipelines. It can be stored locally or online in the variant tools repository (or a local repository maintained by your system adminstrator).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized simulations</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/simulation/custimzedsimu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/simulation/custimzedsimu/</guid>
      <description>Variant Simulation Tools A presentation about variant simulation tools (Sep. 2014)
Variant Simulation Tools is still under development. Development (subversion) versions of Variant Tools and simuPOP are needed to use VST. Also, because of a lack of mature simulation models (only two examples in the submitted paper are available), users are strongly advised to contact me for the creation of any simulation model.
What is Variant Simulation Tools Variant Simulation Tools (VST) is a simulation tool for post-GWAS genetic epidemiological studies using whole-genome or whole-exome next-gen sequencing data, with an emphasis on user-friendliness and reproducibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data exploration/QC</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/data-explorationqc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/data-explorationqc/</guid>
      <description>Data Exploration and Quality Control Overview Quality control is a key step in association analysis. We may use a variety of criteria to clean our data (criteria directly from original vcf file or statistic summary we are interested in). Variants can also be subsetted based on these properties such as variant information, annotations, summary statistics, etc, which are displayed by vtools show fields.
 vtools select and vtools exclude commands implement variant and genotype level data selection and filtering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/discovery/</guid>
      <description>Discover informative variants from a large number of variants Introduction Once you have imported? variants and samples of an exome or whole-genome sequencing project, you are typically facing a master variant table with millions of variants. Depending on the phenotypes of interest and particular research topics, you might want to filter variants for subsequent association analysis, or select variants that are more informative than others for further lab-based analysis. For example, you might be interested in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/development/getinvolved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/development/getinvolved/</guid>
      <description>Report bugs and share ideas People variant tools is currently maintained by Dr. Bo Peng (references) from the Department of Bioinformatics and Computational Biology, MD Anderson Cancer Center, Anthony San Lucas from Dr. Paul Scheet&amp;rsquo;s lab at the University of Texas, MD Anderson Cancer Center, and Gao Wang from Dr. Suzanne Leal&amp;rsquo;s group at the Baylor College of Medicine. Other contributed developers are Min Qiao (UT School of Public Health), Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo gene</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/hugogene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/hugogene/</guid>
      <description>HUGO Gene Nomenclature Committee (HGNC) approved gene names The HUGO Gene Nomenclature Committee (HGNC) has assigned unique gene symbols and names to almost 38,000 human loci, of which around 19,000 are protein coding. genenames.org is a curated online repository of HGNC-approved gene nomenclature and associated resources including links to genomic, proteomic and phenotypic information, as well as dedicated gene family pages.
HGNC The HGNC annotation database is a field database that, by default, annotates another gene name field such as refGene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/import/</guid>
      <description>Import variants, genotypes and related information fields 1. Usage % vtools import -h usage: vtools import [-h] [--build BUILD] [--format FORMAT] [--sample_name [SAMPLE_NAME [SAMPLE_NAME ...]]] [-f] [-j N] [-v {0,1,2}] input_files [input_files ...] x Import variants and related sample genotype from one or more delimiter separated files (e.g. VCF and a number of indel formats). positional arguments: input_files A list of failes that will be imported. The file should be delimiter separated with format described by parameter --format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peng2014_ex2</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/simulation/models/pen2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/simulation/models/pen2/</guid>
      <description>Second example in Peng (2014) Genetic Epidemiology Usage % vtools show simulation Peng2014_ex2 Simulation of case control samples for 20 genes and analyze samples of different sizes (1000, 2000, 3000, 4000 cases and matching number of controls) draw from European, Mexican American (mixed and matched case and control), and from both Asian (cases) and European (controls) populations for a mismatch design. This simulation model has been used to simulate data for the second example in paper &amp;quot;Reproducible Simulations of realistic samples for next-gen sequencing studies using Variant Simulation Tools&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phast cons</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/regions/phast-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/regions/phast-cons/</guid>
      <description>The phastCons database annotates blocks of the genome with conservation scores using the phastCons algorithm (http://compgen.bscb.cornell.edu/phast/help-pages/phastCons.txt). The data that we are using was downloaded from the UCSC genome browser&amp;rsquo;s phastCons46way track that contains conservation data for vertebrates.
PhastConsElements represents the most conserved regions so it covers a significantly percent of genome than the PhastCons database.
PhastConsElements vtools show annotation PhastConsElements Description: PhastCons Conservation Scores Database type: range Number of records: 5,163,775 Distinct ranges: 5,163,775 Reference genome hg19: chr, start, end Field: chr Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 88 Field: start Type: integer Comment: Start position in chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 5,093,542 Range: 1 - 249231389 Field: end Type: integer Comment: End position in chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 5,093,841 Range: 12 - 249231641 Field: name Type: string Comment: Name of conserved region Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 4,358 Field: score Type: integer Comment: Phast cons score from 0 to 1000 Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 580 Range: 177 - 1000  phastCons The following example shows how you can use phastCons to annotate your variants with the average conservation score for the genomic block containing your variant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming in VAT</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/create-your-test/programming-in-vat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/create-your-test/programming-in-vat/</guid>
      <description>Identify genotype - phenotype association Usage % vtools associate -h usage: vtools associate [-h] [--covariates [COVARIATES [COVARIATES ...]]] [--var_info [VAR_INFO [VAR_INFO ...]]] [--geno_info [GENO_INFO [GENO_INFO ...]]] [-m METHODS [METHODS ...]] [-g [GROUP_BY [GROUP_BY ...]]] [-s [COND [COND ...]]] [--genotypes [COND [COND ...]]] [--discard_samples [EXPR [EXPR ...]]] [--discard_variants [EXPR [EXPR ...]]] [--to_db annoDB] [-f] [-j N] [-v {0,1,2}] variants phenotypes Call one or more statistical association tests and return test results as fields to variants tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Annotating variants using multiple annotation databases, a tutorial Getting annotation databases This tutorial demonstrates how to use various databases to annotate variants in a variant tools project. These databases will be automatically downloaded and saved in directory ~/.variant_tools when they are used in a project. The amount of time required to download these databases depends on the speed of your internet connection, server load, and size of the databases. If you do no want to wait for the downloads and if you have enough disk space, you can download all variant tools resources into your local resource directory using the following commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Tutorials These tutorials explain steps that are used to analyze real-world sequencing data. We will try to explain the steps in detail but command output are usually ignored for brevity and confidentiality reasons.
Quick Start Guide This is a 10-minute quick start guide using data from the 1000 genomes project. We encourage you to walk through this minimal real-world example to get a feel for the software and assess its helpfulness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>anno_utils</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/anno_utils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/anno_utils/</guid>
      <description>Annotation utility pipelines Usage % vtools show pipeline anno_utils This file defines a number of pipelines to manipulate variant tools annotation databases. Available pipelines: annFileFromText, annFileFromVcf, annoDB2proj, proj2annoDB Pipeline &amp;quot;annFileFromText&amp;quot;: This pipeline reads a tab, comma or space delimited file, take its header as name of fields, guess the type of each column, and output an .ann file with these fields. The annotation database is assumed to be of type &amp;quot;field&amp;quot; and use the first column as the linked field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bat_gatk33_b37</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/variant-calling/bwa_gatk33_b37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/variant-calling/bwa_gatk33_b37/</guid>
      <description>Variant calling using BWA and GATK best practice pipeline (b37) This is the same pipeline as bwa_gatk33_hg19? but uses build b37 of the human reference genome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>csv</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/csv/</guid>
      <description>Importing and exporting variants in .csv (comma-separated value) format Format description When this format is used to import data, it is similar to the basic? format except that it assumes the use of commas, instead of tabs, as delimiters of the input format.
When this format is used to export variants, it can be used to export arbitrary fields. The command and the resulting ouput are similar to that of the command vtools output --delimiter , (output fields with a delimiter of comma), except that the vtools export --format csv command will properly quote field values when it contains comma, quotation mark etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discordance_rate</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/discordance_rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/discordance_rate/</guid>
      <description>Usage % vtools_report discordance_rate -h usage: vtools_report discordance_rate [-h] [-s [SAMPLES [SAMPLES ...]]] [--genotypes [GENOTYPES [GENOTYPES ...]]] [-v {0,1,2}] Report discordance rate, namely the number of genotype calls that differ between a pair of samples divided by the total number of SNPs for which both calls are non-missing, between pairs of samples. The statistics can be calculated for all samples or selected samples specified by parameter --samples. This command output a n by n matrix with sample names in the header.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>keggPathway</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/misc/keggpathway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/misc/keggpathway/</guid>
      <description>About keggPathway This database provides KEGG pathway IDs and a pathway description for genes with CCDS IDs. If you would like to annotate variants to these KEGG pathways, you first need to annotate your variants with CCDS IDs. Variant tools databases such as ccdsGene annotates variants with CCDS IDs (see example below).
Fields  ccdsId CCDS gene ID KgID Kegg pathway ID KgDesc Description of pathway  keggPathway vtools show annotation keggPathway -v2 Annotation database keggPathway (version 20110823) Description: kegg pathway for CCDS genes Database type: attribute Number of records: 19,584 Reference genome *: [&#39;ccdsId&#39;] Field: ccdsId Type: string Comment: CCDS gene ID Missing entries: 0 Unique entries: 6,949 Field: KgID Type: string Comment: Kegg pathway ID Missing entries: 0 Unique entries: 209 Field: KgDesc Type: string Comment: Description of pathway Missing entries: 0 Unique entries: 209  Examples First we need to use dbNSFP in our project to annotate our variants with CCDS IDs:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>md5sumd</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/utilities/_md5sumd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/utilities/_md5sumd/</guid>
      <description>Generate and check with MD5 checksum for files and directories ChangeLog  Apr. 19, 2013: Minor error message improvement. Mar. 20, 2013: Version 1.0.1 with format change to handle non-ASCII filenames. February, 2013: Initial public release of version 1.0.  Download  Source code: md5sumd? (use python or python3 to run it) Windows executable: md5sumd.exe? MacOSX executable: md5sumd_macosx.zip? (decompress to get a binary file)  NOTE: If you have a filesystem with non-ASCII filenames encoded not in UTF-8, the directory md5sum might not work across platform unless you use the Python 3 version of the script (use python3 on source code).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mut_sequence</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/mut_sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/mut_sequence/</guid>
      <description>Mutated sequence around variant site Usage Function mut_sequence(chr, start, end) returns the mutated sequence between start and end on chromosome chr of the reference genome (primary reference genome unless parameter --build is used to specify an alternative reference genome). If end is unspecified, mut_sequence(chr, pos) returns the mutated allele at the specified location.
Simply put, function mut_sequence in
% vtools output variant chr pos &#39;mut_sequence(chr, pos)&#39;  returns the alternative allele at the variant site for SNPs, - for deletion, and XXXR for insertion of XXX before reference allele R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sbNSFP</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/dbnsfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/dbnsfp/</guid>
      <description>dbNSFP (:skin vtools-annotation
(:toc
dbNSFP is an annotation database for non-synonymous SNPs assembled by Xiaoming Liu from the University of Texas School of Public Health (see citation below). With variant tools you can use the dbNSFP database or dbNSFP-light (a version with fewer features) - see which features are offered for each database version below.
dbNSFP There can be frequent changes of name and their meanings of the fields across versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association analysis</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/association-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/association-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Association Analysis Statistical Tests for Genotype/phenotype Associations The VAT association command We will introduce the basic usage of this command without diving into each association test. For a complete demonstration of all the tests please refer to the documentation for VAT (on the sidebar of this webpage).
Getting started The general interface of vtools associate is as follows
% vtools associate -h usage: vtools associate [-h] [--covariates [COVARIATES [COVARIATES .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C-alpha test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/c_alpha-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/c_alpha-test/</guid>
      <description>C-alpha Test for Protective Variants Introduction This implements the {$C(\alpha)$} test (Neale et al 2011[^Benjamin M. Neale, Manuel A. Rivas, Benjamin F. Voight, David Altshuler, Bernie Devlin, Marju Orho-Melander, Sekar Kathiresan, Shaun M. Purcell, Kathryn Roeder and Mark J. Daly (2011) Testing for an Unusual Distribution of Rare Variants. PLoS Genetics doi:10.1371/journal.pgen.1001322. http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1001322^]) for disease traits, to test for the hypothesis of rare variants disease association under the particular assumption that rare variants observed in cases and controls is a mixture of phenotypically deleterious, protective and neutral variants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized annotation databases</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/customized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/customized/</guid>
      <description>Create annotation database Because you write your own .ann file, please consider using pipelines in anno_utils, which can usually create .ann file from some data sources with pre-defined formats.
Define a new annotation database If you would like to use an annotation source that is not currently supported by variant tools, you could send us and email if the data source is publicly available, or write an annotation specification file to create your own annotation database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENCODE</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/misc/encode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/misc/encode/</guid>
      <description>ENCODE Download bigWig and bigBed files and use the track() function to annotate variants. More details will follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EntrezGene</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/entrezgene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/entrezgene/</guid>
      <description>EntrezGene % vtools show annotation EntrezGene.DB Annotation database EntrezGene (version 20131028) Description: Entrez Gene (www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?db=gene) is NCBI&#39;s database for gene-specific information. It does not include all known or predicted genes; instead Entrez Gene focuses on the genomes that have been completely sequenced, that have an active research community to contribute gene- specific information, or that are scheduled for intense sequence analysis. This database contains Entrez gene info database for Homo Sapiens, downloaded from ftp://ftp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomic super dups</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/regions/genomic-super-dups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/regions/genomic-super-dups/</guid>
      <description>See this blog Why You Should Care About Segmental Duplications for some nice explanation.
vtools show annotation genomicSuperDups -v2 Annotation database genomicSuperDups (version hg19_20130626) Description: Duplications of &amp;gt;1000 Bases of Non-RepeatMasked Sequence (&amp;gt;90 percent similar). Database type: range Number of records: 51,599 Distinct ranges: 40,832 Reference genome hg19: chr, start, end Field: chr Type: string Comment: Reference sequence chromosome or scaffold Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 80 Field: start Type: integer Comment: Start position in chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 30,451 Range: 1 - 249235635 Field: end Type: integer Comment: End position in chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 30,690 Range: 1832 - 249240008 Field: name Type: string Comment: Other chromosome involved Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 30,525 Field: otherChr Type: string Comment: Other chromosome or scaffold Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 80 Field: otherStart Type: integer Comment: Start position of other region Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 30,451 Range: 0 - 249235634 Field: otherEnd Type: integer Comment: End position in chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 30,690 Range: 1832 - 249240008 Field: otherSize Type: integer Comment: Total size of other chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 80 Range: 19913 - 249250621 Field: alignL Type: integer Comment: spaces/positions in alignment Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 13,141 Range: 1001 - 777920 Field: indelN Type: integer Comment: number of indels Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 436 Range: 0 - 993 Field: indelS Type: integer Comment: indel spaces Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 4,617 Range: 0 - 92315 Field: matchB Type: integer Comment: aligned bases that match Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 12,497 Range: 1000 - 766171 Field: mismatchB Type: integer Comment: aligned bases that do not match Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 12,623 Range: 900 - 766171 Field: transitionsB Type: integer Comment: number of transitions Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 2,659 Range: 0 - 9703 Field: transversionsB Type: integer Comment: number of transversions Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 1,880 Range: 0 - 5953 Field: fracMatch Type: float Comment: fraction of matching bases Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 1,442 Range: 0 - 4002 Field: fracMatchIndel Type: float Comment: fraction of matching bases with indels Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 21,193 Range: 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/help/</guid>
      <description>Usage of variant tools commands Structure of commands vtools uses a subcommand system that is similar to svn. For example, command
% vtools select variant &#39;sift_score &amp;lt; 0.05&#39; -t table  consists of:
 command vtools subcommand select that specify operation, positional arguments variant that specifies a variant table and &#39;sift_score &amp;lt; 0.05&#39; that specify operant, which in this case are the variant table to select from, and condition by which the variants are selected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style sheet</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/administration/stylesheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/administration/stylesheet/</guid>
      <description>table.zebra tr:nth-child(odd) {
background-color: #f3f3f3;  }
table.zebra {
padding-top: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px; /* font-family: &amp;quot;Lucida Sans Unicode&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Lucida Grande&amp;quot;, Sans-Serif; */ font-size: 14px; /* margin: 45px; */ /* width: 480px; */ text-align: left; border-collapse: collapse;  }
table.zebra th {
font-size: 16px; font-weight: normal; padding: 10px 8px; /* color: #039; */  }
table.zebra td {
padding: 8px;  /* text-align:left; */
/* color: #669; */  }
.escaped {</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/update/</guid>
      <description>Add new or update existing variant and genotype info fields 1. Usage % vtools update -h usage: vtools update [-h] [--from_file FROM_FILE [FROM_FILE ...]] [--build BUILD] [--format FORMAT] [-j N] [--sample_name [SAMPLE_NAME [SAMPLE_NAME ...]]] [--set [EXPR [EXPR ...]]] [--from_stat [EXPR [EXPR ...]]] [-s [COND [COND ...]]] [--genotypes [COND [COND ...]]] [-v {0,1,2}] table Add or update fields of existing variants and genotype from other fields, statistics of genotypes and genotype info, or files that annotate variants or their locations (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weighted methods</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/weighted-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/weighted-methods/</guid>
      <description>Weighted Burden Test for Disease and Quantitative Traits Introduction This implements a collection of weighted aggregation tests. Different from plain aggregation methods? which assumes equal contribution of each locus from the genetic region under investigation, the weighted methods assigns a &amp;ldquo;weight&amp;rdquo; to each variant site such that each site differs from another by the weight they are assigned, and these weights will contribute to the aggregated &amp;ldquo;burden&amp;rdquo;, e.g., {$$X=\sum_i^N\omega_iX_i$$} where {$\omega_i$}&amp;rsquo;s are the weights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bwa_gatk28_hg19</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/variant-calling/bwa_gatk28_hg19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/variant-calling/bwa_gatk28_hg19/</guid>
      <description>Calling variants using BWA and GATK best practice pipeline Usage % vtools show pipeline bwa_gatk28_hg19 A pipeline to align raw reads from fastq or BAW/SAM files using BWA and GATK best practice. It uses hg19 of human reference genome and assumes paired-end reads in plain text and compressed formats. Available pipelines: align, call Pipeline &amp;quot;align&amp;quot;: Align raw reads from input files using bwa, gatk, and picard. This pipeline accepts raw input files in plain text format, SAM/BAM format, and their compressed versions (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dbSNP</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/dbsnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/dbsnp/</guid>
      <description>dbSNP annotation databases The default version of our dbSNP annotation is currently referring to dbSNP143 (using hg38 coordinates) as shown below. However, users can also retrieve older versions of dbSNP: dbSNP141, dbSNP138, dbSNP137, dbSNP135, dbSNP132, dbSNP131, dbSNP130, dbSNP129. The 129 and 130 versions use hg18 as a reference genome, 131, 132, 135, 137, 138 and 141 use hg19 and 143 uses hg38. The archived versions can be used by a variant tools project by referring to their specific names - for example: dbSNP-hg18_129.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plink</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/plink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/plink/</guid>
      <description>Import variants and sample genotypes from PLINK format Introduction PLINK is a widely used program for analyzing genotypic data for Genome-wide Association Studies (GWAS). It can be considered as standard input format for genotyping array data. An intermediate type of genetic data between genotyping arrays and exome sequencing is the exome genotyping array, or exome chip. Unlike its GWAS counterpart which focuses on relatively common variants, exome chips contain primarily non-singleton coding variants seen in existing whole genome and exome sequencing data, plus a small proportion of non-protein-altering variants such as GWAS tag SNPs, ancestry informative markers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sam_info</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/sam_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/sam_info/</guid>
      <description>Output coverage and other information of variants in specified SAM/BAM files This command is deprecated with the new track function with BAM tracks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>track</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/track/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/track/</guid>
      <description>Extract annotation from external files Usage Function track(filename, field) returns annotation information at column col (optional) in file filename, at position (chr, pos at primary or alternative reference genome) of each variant. For example, function
% vtools output variant chr pos ref alt &amp;quot;track(&#39;1000g.vcf.gz&#39;, &#39;info&#39;)&amp;quot;  single quote (&#39;) should be used for string literals in SQL functions. Double quote (&amp;quot;) should be avoided although it sometimes works.
output the &amp;ldquo;info&amp;rdquo; column of file 1000g.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transmission</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/transmission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/transmission/</guid>
      <description>Identification of recessive and de novo variants for family-based design This pipeline is an extension to command vtools_report transmission, the differences are
 vtools_report transmission find recessive and de novo mutations and create variant tables for each offspring. This pipeline assumes the first offspring is the affected one and remove de novo and recessive variants of the second offspring from the list. It creates a single variant table for the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genotype</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/genotype/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/genotype/</guid>
      <description>genotypes of one or more samples Usage Genotype information for a variant is not directly available in variant tools commands such as vtools output because these commands only output variant info or annotation fields. Function genotype can be used to retrieve genotypes of one or more samples from the genotype tables. In its single-sample mode, this function accepts a sample name and an optional field to display,
genotype(sample_name, params=&#39;&#39;)  where params can have be multiple parameters joined by &amp;amp;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illumnina</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/illumina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/illumina/</guid>
      <description>Pipelines to assist the analysis of illumina data Usage $ vtools show pipeline illumina A pipeline to handle illumina data prepared by CASAVA 1.8+. It imports variants from SNPs.vcf and Indel.vcf of multiple samples, separate maxgt and poly into different projects, calculate a few standard statistics and apply a few filters. All results are saved as variant tools snapshots. This pipeline uses command vtools so multi-processing is not supported. Available pipelines: load_data Pipeline &amp;quot;load_data&amp;quot;: This pipeline accepts a list of directories under which SNPs and Indels are listed in files Variations/SNPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KBAC test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/kbac-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/kbac-test/</guid>
      <description>Kernel Based Adaptive Clustering Method Introduction This is implementation for the KBAC statistic in Liu and Leal 2010[^Dajiang J. Liu and Suzanne M. Leal (2010) A Novel Adaptive Method for the Analysis of Next-Generation Sequencing Data to Detect Complex Trait Associations with Rare Variants Due to Gene Main Effects and Interactions. PLoS Genetics doi:10.1371/journal.pgen.1001156. http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1001156^]. It carries out case-control association testing for rare variants for whole exome association studies. Briefly, consider a gene of length n which harbors m rare variants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenotype</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/phenotype/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/phenotype/</guid>
      <description>Import and manipulate phenotypes 1. Usage % vtools phenotype -h usage: vtools phenotype [-h] [-f [INPUT_FILE [INPUT_FILE ...]]] [--set [EXPRESSION [EXPRESSION ...]]] [--from_stat [EXPRESSION [EXPRESSION ...]]] [--output [EXPRESSION [EXPRESSION ...]]] [-j N] [-g [COND [COND ...]]] [-s [COND [COND ...]]] [--header [HEADER [HEADER ...]]] [-d DELIMITER] [--na NA] [-l LIMIT] [-v {0,1,2}] Import phenotypes from a file, or set phenotypes to constants, or to summary statistics of sample genotype fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-assoc analysis</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/post-assoc-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/post-assoc-analysis/</guid>
      <description> Representing and Interpreting Association Results </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic statistics</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/administration/trafficstat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/administration/trafficstat/</guid>
      <description>table.zebra tr:nth-child(odd) {
background-color: #f3f3f3;  }
table.zebra {
padding-top: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px; /* font-family: &amp;quot;Lucida Sans Unicode&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Lucida Grande&amp;quot;, Sans-Serif; */ font-size: 14px; /* margin: 45px; */ /* width: 480px; */ text-align: left; border-collapse: collapse;  }
table.zebra th {
font-size: 16px; font-weight: normal; padding: 10px 8px; /* color: #039; */  }
table.zebra td {
padding: 8px;  /* text-align:left; */
/* color: #669; */  }
.escaped {</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable thresholds</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/variable-thresholds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/variable-thresholds/</guid>
      <description>Varible Thresholds Methods for Disease and Quantitative Traits Introduction This implements the variable thresholds version of aggregation methods?. Similar to the VT? method, the VariableThresholdsBt and VariableThresholdsQt tests use a variable thresholds definition for the rare variants being considered such that multiple test statistics are calculated for an aggregation unit. The final statistic is taken as the one that gives the best result. Type I error is controlled due to the use of permutation testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bwa_gatk28_b37</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/variant-calling/bwa_gatk28_b37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/variant-calling/bwa_gatk28_b37/</guid>
      <description>Calling variants using BWA and GATK best practice pipeline (b37) This pipeline is identical to bwa_gatk28_hg19? except that it uses the b37 reference genome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cytoBand</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/regions/cytoband/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/regions/cytoband/</guid>
      <description>cytoBand defines cytogenic bands. This annotation source gives the approximate location of these bands as seen on Giemsa-stained chromosomes. This data was downloaded from the UCSC Genome Browser database (http://genome.ucsc.edu/cgi-bin/hgTables).
The following fields are available for annotation.
vtools show annotation cytoBand -v2 DEBUG: Opening project temp.proj DEBUG: Loading annotation database cytoBand DEBUG: Loading annotation database gwasCatalog Annotation database cytoBand (version hg19_20111216) Description: Cyto Band Database type: range Number of records: 862 Number of distinct ranges: 862 Reference genome hg19: [&#39;chr&#39;, &#39;begin&#39;, &#39;end&#39;] Field: chr Type: chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 24 Field: begin Type: integer Comment: start position on chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 667 Range: 1 - 243700001 Field: end Type: integer Comment: end position on chromosome Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 690 Range: 2200000 - 249250621 Field: name Type: string Comment: name of cytogenic band Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 259 Field: gieStain Type: string Comment: giemsa stain results Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 8  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>knownGene</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/knowngene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/knowngene/</guid>
      <description>The knownGene database is based on the UCSC Genome Browser knownGene track. knownGene shows gene predictions based on data from RefSeq, Genbank, CCDS and UniProt. If you would like to annotate your variants to these genes, you can use the simpler knownGene database. If you would like to determine the exons that your variants are in, use the knownGene_exon database. See the available annotation fields for each database below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>linkage-physical map</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/linkagephysicalmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/linkagephysicalmap/</guid>
      <description>The rutgersMap database was created from Rutgers Combined Linkage-Phsycal Map[^T. C. Matise, F. Chen, W. Chen, F. M. De La Vega, M. Hansen, C. He, F. C.L. Hyland, G. C. Kennedy, X. Kong, S. S. Murray, J. S. Ziegle, W. C.L. Stewart and S. Buyske (2007). A second-generation combined linkage physical map of the human genome. Genome Research^]. The current version contains interpolated genetic positions for variants from dbSNP build 134.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rsname</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/rsname/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/rsname/</guid>
      <description>Importing variants from a list of dbSNP iDs (rsnames) Format description % vtools show format rsname Import variants (chr, pos, ref, alt) that are queried from dbSNP database using provided rsnames Columns: None defined, cannot export to this format variant: chr Obtain chromosome from dbSNP by rsname pos Obtain position from dbSNP by rsname ref Obtain reference allele from dbSNP by rsname alt Obtain alternative allele from dbSNP by rsname Format parameters: sep delimiter used to separate input fields (default: &#39;,&#39;) rsname_col Index for the column with rsname (default: 1) dbfile Name of an attached dbSNP database or path to the dbSNP database in sqlite format (default: dbSNP- hg19_138.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sequence</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/sequence/</guid>
      <description>Output DNA and protein sequence at specified chromosome regions Usage % vtools_report sequence -h usage: vtools_report sequence [-h] [--build [BUILD]] [--numbered [{left,right}]] [--char_per_line CHAR_PER_LINE] [--transcribe [GENE [GENE ...]]] [--translate [GENE [GENE ...]]] [--mark [MARK [MARK ...]]] [--mark_complement] [--mark_reverse] [--hide_unmatched] [-v {0,1,2,3}] regions [regions ...] positional arguments: regions One or more chromosome regions in the format of chr :start-end (e.g. chr21:33,031,597-33,041,570), Field:Value from a region-based annotation database (e.g. refGene.name2:TRIM2 or refGene_exon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANNOVAR</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/annovar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/annovar/</guid>
      <description>Gene-based annotation through ANNOVAR Usage % vtools show pipeline ANNOVAR Pipeline to call ANNOVAR and import results as variant info fields. Available pipelines: geneanno Pipeline &amp;quot;geneanno&amp;quot;: This pipeline exports variants in specified variant table (parameter --var_table, default to variant), executes ANNOVAR&#39;s gene- based annotation (annotate_variantion.pl --geneanno), and imports specified fields from output of the command. Four fields (two for all variants and two for exonic variants) will be imported unless you disable some of them using parameters --variant_info and --exonic_info.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cumtomized</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/new/</guid>
      <description>Specification of external file formats Roles of format specification in variant tools: Variant tools can import and export text files (or gzipped text files) in delimiter-separated format, namely records that are separated into columns by delimiters such as tab, space or comma. The file format must be variant-oriented (storing one or more variants by line), with the exception of sample-based PLINK format which is preprocessed internally into variant-oriented form for import.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database of Genomic Variants</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/databaseof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/databaseof/</guid>
      <description> s
Database of Genomic Variants Database of genomic variants is a curated catalogue of human genomic structural variation. It is a range-based database that shows the range of such variants.
% vtools show annotation DGV -v2 Annotation database DGV (version hg19_20130723) Description: Database of Genomic Variants, a curated catalogue of human genomic structural variation. Database type: range Number of records: 202,430 Distinct ranges: 199,827 Reference genome hg19: chr, start, end Field: variantaccession Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 202,430 Field: chr Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 24 Field: start Type: integer Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 189,925 Range: 1 - 249205967 Field: end Type: integer Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 189,604 Range: 16629 - 249206446 Field: varianttype Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 2 Field: variantsubtype Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 9 Field: reference Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 55 Field: pubmedid Type: integer Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 55 Range: 12058347 - 23290073 Field: method Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 31 Field: platform Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 49 Field: mergedvariants Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 1 Field: supportingvariants Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 198,642 Field: mergedorsample Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 2 Field: frequency Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 65 Field: samplesize Type: integer Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 37 Range: 0 - 6533 Field: observedgains Type: integer Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 188 Range: 0 - Field: observedlosses Type: integer Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 825 Range: 0 - Field: cohortdescription Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 6 Field: genes Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 25,687 Field: samples Type: string Missing entries: 0 Unique Entries: 67,200  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBT test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/rbt-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/rbt-test/</guid>
      <description>Replication Based Test for Protective Variants Introduction This is implementation for the replication base test in Ionita-Laza et al 2011[^Iuliana Ionita-Laza, Joseph D. Buxbaum, Nan M. Laird and Christoph Lange (2011) A New Testing Strategy to Identify Rare Variants with Either Risk or Protective Effect on Disease. PLoS Genetics doi:10.1371/journal.pgen.1001289. http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1001289^]. The key of this method is replication, i.e., in the two-sided test of RBT it computes evidences to reject each of the two hypothesis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SKAT test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/skat-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/skat-test/</guid>
      <description>SNP-set (Sequence) Kernel Association Test Method Introduction Details Command interface vtools show test SKAT Name: SKAT Description: SKAT (Wu et al 2011) wrapper of its original R implementation usage: vtools associate --method SKAT [-h] [--name NAME] [-k {linear,linear.weighted,IBS,IBS.weighted,quadratic,2wayIX}] [--beta_param BETA_PARAM BETA_PARAM] [-m {davies,liu,liu.mod,optimal}] [-i {fixed,random}] [--logistic_weights PARAM PARAM] [-r [CORR [CORR ...]]] [--missing_cutoff MISSING_CUTOFF] [--resampling N] [--small_sample] [--resampling_kurtosis N] {quantitative,disease} SNP-set (Sequence) Kernel Association Test (Wu et al 2011). This is a wrapper for the R package &amp;quot;SKAT&amp;quot; implemented &amp;amp; maintained by Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lifttover</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/liftover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/liftover/</guid>
      <description>Adding coordinates from an alternative reference genome 1. Usage % vtools liftover -h usage: vtools liftover [-h] [--flip] [-v STD[LOG]] build Convert coordinates of existing variants to alternative coordinates in an alternative reference genome. The UCSC liftover tool will be automatically downloaded if it is not available. positional arguments: build Name of the alternative reference genome optional arguments: -h, --help show this help message and exit --flip Flip primary and alternative reference genomes so that the specified build will become the primary reference genome of the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>refGene</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/refgene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/refgene/</guid>
      <description>The RefGene database was created from the UCSC database. RefGene specifies known human protein-coding and non-protein-coding genes taken from the NCBI RNA reference sequences collection (RefSeq). If you would like to annotate your variants to genes, you can use the simpler refGene database. If you would like to determine the exons that your variants are in, use the refGene_exon database. See the available annotation fields for each database below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>samples</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/samples/</guid>
      <description>Samples that harbor the variant Usage The samples function is similar to genotype but it returns name of samples that contain the variant. When you use the function in command vtools output var_table samples(), this function will be evaluated for each variant in the variant table var_table. In its basic form,
samples()  returns a list of comma-separated names of samples that contain the variant, regardless the type of variant (homozygote etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>trans_ratio</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/trans_ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/trans_ratio/</guid>
      <description>Transition-transversion Ratio About `vtools_report trans_ratio This command counts the number of transition and transversion variants and calculates its ratio. The expected ratio is 2 in human pseudo-genes (after the exclusion of transitions at CpG sites).
Usage % vtools_report trans_ratio -h usage: vtools_report trans_ratio [-h] -n NUM_FIELD [--group_by [GROUP_BY [GROUP_BY ...]]] [-v {0,1,2}] table This command counts the number of transition (A&amp;lt;-&amp;gt;G and C&amp;lt;-&amp;gt;T) and transversion variants (others) and calculate its ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CancerGeneCensus</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/cancergenecensus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/genes/cancergenecensus/</guid>
      <description>Data source This database contains variants from the Cancer Genome Project. It is &amp;ldquo;an ongoing effort to catalogue those genes for which mutations have been causally implicated in cancer. The original census and analysis was published in Nature Reviews Cancer and supplemental analysis information related to the paper is also available. Currently, more than 1% of all human genes are implicated via mutation in cancer. Of these, approximately 90% have somatic mutations in cancer, 20% bear germline mutations that predispose to cancer and 10% show both somatic and germline mutations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exome Sequencing Project</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/exomesequencingpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/exomesequencingpro/</guid>
      <description>Variants from the Exome Sequencing Project (ESP) The EVS annotation source contains exome sequencing variants retrieved from the Exome Variant Server (EVS) for the NHLBI Exome Sequencing Project (ESP). The evs annotation data was generated from approximately 2500 exomes and evs_5400 from approximately 5400 exomes. (7500 exomes are the next milestone for this project in the next couple of months - see their website for project details: http://evs.gs.washington.edu/EVS/). Currently minor allele frequencies are given for European American and African American populations - see below for additional fields that you can use for variant selection and annotation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetaSKAT analysis</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/metaskat-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/jointconditional-association-analysis/metaskat-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Association Analysis with the Meta SKAT R Program The R extension for RTest is available HERE. For details on the format of this script please refer to the RTest method documentation?.
Example We analyze association with a binary trait named X6 conditioning on 3 covariates X8, X9, X10. Group information is provided by race. For each testing group, data is first cleaned by removing samples missing greater than 50% calls, then by removing variants missing 50% calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RareCover test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/rarecover-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/rarecover-test/</guid>
      <description>A &amp;ldquo;Covering Algorithm&amp;rdquo; for Rare and Low Frequency Variants Introduction The RareCover test in Bhatia et al 2010[^Gaurav Bhatia, Vikas Bansal, Olivier Harismendy, Nicholas J. Schork, Eric J. Topol, Kelly Frazer and Vineet Bafna (2010) A Covering Method for Detecting Genetic Associations between Rare Variants and Common Phenotypes. PLoS Computational Biology doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1000954. http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1000954^] is an efficient heuristic greedy algorithm to find an optimized combination of variants in a loci with the strongest association signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>in_table</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/in_table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/in_table/</guid>
      <description> Test membership of variants in variant tables Usage The in_table function is a simple function used to test is a variant is in a specified variant table. It accepts the name of a variant table and returns 1 if the variant belong to this table, and 0 otherwise.
in_table(&#39;table_name&#39;)  Details For example, command
% vtools admin --load_snapshot vt_simple % vtools show tables  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>show</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/show/</guid>
      <description>Display project and system information 1. Usage % vtools show -h usage: vtools show [-h] [-l N] [-v {0,1,2,3}] [{project,tables,table,samples,phenotypes,genotypes,fields,annotations,annotation,track,formats,format,tests,test,runtime_options,runtime_option,snapshot,snapshots}] [items [items ...]] Output information of all system and project related items such as variant tables, samples, phenotypes, annotation databases and fields. positional arguments: {project,tables,table,samples,phenotypes,genotypes,fields,annotations,annotation,track,formats,format,tests,test,runtime_options,runtime_option,snapshot,snapshots} Type of information to display, which can be &#39;project&#39; for summary of a project, &#39;tables&#39; for all variant tables (or all tables if --verbosity=2), &#39;table TBL&#39; for details of a specific table TBL, &#39;samples [COND]&#39; for sample name, files from which samples are imported, and associated phenotypes (can be supressed by option --verbosity 0) of all or selected samples, &#39;phenotypes [P1 P2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>snpEff</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/snpeff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/snpeff/</guid>
      <description>Variant effect provided by snpEFF Usage This pipeline exports variants in VCF format, call snpEff to predict its effect, and import the result as an variant info field EFF.
% vtools show pipeline snpEff A pipeline to call snpEff to annotate variants. Available pipelines: eff Pipeline &amp;quot;eff&amp;quot;: This pipeline export variants in VCF format, call snpEff to annotate it, and import the EFF info as an information field. This pipeline will automatically download appropriate snpEff database (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tped</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/tped/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/tped/</guid>
      <description>PLINK/TPED format About TPED format Many software applications for linkage and association studies (e.g. plink, merlin) accept PED/MAP format. The map file records basic information about markers, the Ped file contains sample genotype. Whereas variant tools can easily export in MAP format, it is difficult to export in PED format because this format is not variant oriented (output by variant).
Fortunately, PLINK accepts a transposed PED format (TPED) that is variant oriented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>variant_stat</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/variant_stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/variant_stat/</guid>
      <description>Counting variants of different types, optionally by samples Usage % vtools_report variant_stat -h usage: vtools_report variant_stat [-h] [-s [SAMPLES [SAMPLES ...]]] [-g [GROUP_BY [GROUP_BY ...]]] [-v {0,1,2}] table Command &#39;vtools variant_stat&#39; calculates the number of snps, insertions, deletions and substitutions for groups of samples with some size metrics to characterize the indels. The statistics can be calculated for all samples (effectively for the master variant table when parameters --samples and --group_by are ignored), a subset of samples (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KING</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/king/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/pipelines/other-pipelines/king/</guid>
      <description>Global ancestry and kinship inference Usage % vtools show pipeline KING Pipeline to call KING to perform global ancestry and kinship inference, and import ancestry analysis results as phenotypes into sample table. Available pipelines: king Pipeline &amp;quot;king&amp;quot;: This pipeline exports genotypes in specified variant table (parameter --var_table, default to variant) for specified samples (parameter --samples, default to all samples), executes PLINK&#39;s LD pruning, (R^2&amp;lt;0.5) and analysis selected variants using KING&#39;s population ancestry and kingship analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other functions</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/otherfunctions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/functions/otherfunctions/</guid>
      <description>Other customized SQL functions vcf_variant: Output variants in vcf format with padding alleles Function vcf_variant(chr, pos, ref, alt, name=&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;) returns a string that represent variants in vcf format. If the variant is a SNV, the output merely connects input by tab (&amp;rsquo;\t&amp;rsquo;). If the variant is an indel, it will pad reference (for insertion) or alternative (for deletion) allele with the allele before variant, adjust position, and generate an output that is acceptable by vcf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VT test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/vt-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/vt-test/</guid>
      <description>Variable Thresholds Test for Case Control Data Analysis Introduction The variable thresholds method (VT, Price et al 2010[^Alkes L. Price, Gregory V. Kryukov, Paul I.W. de Bakker, Shaun M. Purcell, Jeff Staples, Lee-Jen Wei and Shamil R. Sunyaev (2010) Pooled Association Tests for Rare Variants in Exon-Resequencing Studies. The American Journal of Human Genetics doi:10.1016/j.ajhg.2010.04.005. http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0002929710002077^]) tests for association between phenotypic values (case control or quantitative traits) with individuals&amp;rsquo; genotype &amp;ldquo;score&amp;rdquo; subject to a variable MAF threshold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gwasCatalog</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/gwas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/gwas/</guid>
      <description>The gwasCatalog is NHGRI&amp;rsquo;s collection of Genome-Wide Association (GWA) Studies SNPs. We downloaded the data for this annotation source from the UCSC Genome Browser database (http://genome.ucsc.edu/cgi-bin/hgTables?command=start). You can use this annotation source as a position, range or field-based annotation source. Examples for usage as a range-based and field-based annotation source are given on this page. (By default the usage for this annotation source is a position-based annotation source).
Usage Here are the available gwasCatalog fields for annotation and filtering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inbreeding_coefficient</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/inbreeding_coefficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/inbreeding_coefficient/</guid>
      <description>Calculation inbreeding coefficient for individual samples vtools_report inbreeding_coefficient calculates the {$F$} statistic at single individual sample level from genotype data. It measures the reduction in heterozygosity for given genomic region of samples, compare to expected heterozygosity level under Hardy-Weinberg Equilibrium. For a two allelic locus, {$$P(AA)=p^2(1-F)+pF$$} {$$P(aa)=q^2(1-F)+qF$$} {$$P(Aa)=2pq(1-F)$$} We compute estimate for {$F$} as {$\hat{F}=1-\frac{#observed(Aa)}{#expected(Aa)}$}
Variants included for calculation of {$F$} must be under HWE and be bi-allelic. Tri-allelic loci are automatically excluded from calculation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>map</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/map/</guid>
      <description>Import variants from file without ref and alt alleles Introduction From time to time, you might get a list of variants in map format, or as a list with only chromosome and position information. Reference and alternative alleles are not specified because the variants are from GWA studies with well-defined reference and alternative alleles. In this case, you can use format map, which automatically retrieve reference and alternative alleles from a specified dbSNP database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>use</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/use/</guid>
      <description>Use an annotation database 1. Usage % vtools use -h usage: vtools use [-h] [--as NAME] [-l [LINKED_BY [LINKED_BY ...]]] [--anno_type {variant,position,range,field}] [--linked_fields [LINKED_FIELDS [LINKED_FIELDS ...]]] [-f [FILES [FILES ...]]] [--rebuild] [-j N] [-v {0,1,2}] source Link an annotation database to the project, download it from the variant tools website or build it from source if needed. positional arguments: source Use an annotation database ($source.DB or $source.DB.gz) if it is available, download or build the database if a description file ($source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HapMap</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/hapmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/hapmap/</guid>
      <description>Usage Population-specific databases from the HapMap project. They provide population-specific variant count and frequences.
% vtools show annotations hapmap -v0 hapmap_ASW_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_ASW_freq hapmap_CEU_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_CEU_freq hapmap_CHB_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_CHB_freq hapmap_CHD_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_CHD_freq hapmap_GIH_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_GIH_freq hapmap_JPT_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_JPT_freq hapmap_LWK_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_LWK_freq hapmap_MEX_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_MEX_freq hapmap_MKK_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_MKK_freq hapmap_TSI_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_TSI_freq hapmap_YRI_freq-hg18_20100817 hapmap_YRI_freq  Details % vtools show annotation hapmap_CEU_freq Annotation database hapmap_CEU_freq (version hg18_20100817) Description: Allele frequency information of SNP markers of the CEU population of phase II and III of the HAPMAP project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSS test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/wss-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/wss-test/</guid>
      <description>Weighted Sum Statistic via Rank Test Introduction The method proposed by Madsen and Browning 2009[^Bo Eskerod Madsen and Sharon R. Browning (2009) A Groupwise Association Test for Rare Mutations Using a Weighted Sum Statistic. PLoS Genetics doi:10.1371/journal.pgen.1000384. http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1000384^] first introduced the idea of assigning &amp;ldquo;weights&amp;rdquo; to rare variants within a genetic region before they are collapsed. In this case the variants having higher weights will have more substantial contribution to the collapsed variant score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>select</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/select/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/select/</guid>
      <description>Select variants from a variant table 1. Usage % vtools select -h usage: vtools select [-h] [-s [COND [COND ...]]] [-t [TABLE [DESC ...]]] [-c | -o [FIELDS [FIELDS ...]]] [--header [HEADER [HEADER ...]]] [-d DELIMITER] [--na NA] [-l N] [--build BUILD] [-g [FIELD [FIELD ...]]] [--all] [--order_by FIELD [FIELD ...]] [-v {0,1,2}] from_table [condition [condition ...]] Select variants according to properties (variant and annotation fields) and membership (samples) of variant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transmission</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/transmission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/transmission/</guid>
      <description>Locate de novo, recessive and other variants that are transmitted from parents to offspring The inconsistent option of this command is not completed yet.
Usage % vtools_report transmission -h usage: vtools_report transmission [-h] [--parents PARENTS PARENTS] [--offspring OFFSPRING [OFFSPRING ...]] [--denovo [DENOVO [DENOVO ...]]] [--recessive [RECESSIVE [RECESSIVE ...]]] [--inconsistent [INCONSISTENT [INCONSISTENT ...]]] [-v {0,1,2}] optional arguments: -h, --help show this help message and exit --parents PARENTS PARENTS Names of parents, which should uniquely identify two samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thousand Genomes</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/thousand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/annotation/variants/thousand/</guid>
      <description>thousandGenomes The samples for the 1000 Genomes Project mostly are anonymous and have no associated medical or phenotype data. Variants in this annotation database are sometimes considered to be &amp;lsquo;neutral&amp;rsquo; and could be removed if the goal of a study is to look for variants with high penetrance that dispose to rare Mendelian diseases. This database contains all of the variants supplied by the 1000 Genomes Project. The original vcf file can be obtained from here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aSum test</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/asum-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/applications/association/single-gene-association-methods/asum-test/</guid>
      <description>Data-adaptive Sum Test for Protective and Deleterious Variants Introduction The data-adaptive sum test (aSum) by Han and Pan 2010[^Fang Han and Wei Pan (2010) A Data-Adaptive Sum Test for Disease Association with Multiple Common or Rare Variants. Human Heredity doi:10.1159/000288704. http://www.karger.com/doi/10.1159/000288704^] is the first method that took into consideration the difference in direction of effects (protective or deleterious) of rare variants in the same genetic region analyzed by a rare variant association test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>exclude</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/exclude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/exclude/</guid>
      <description>Exclude variants that match certain criteria 1. Usage % vtools exclude -h usage: vtools exclude [-h] [-s [COND [COND ...]]] [-t [TABLE [DESC ...]]] [-c | -o [FIELDS [FIELDS ...]]] [--header [HEADER [HEADER ...]]] [-d DELIMITER] [--na NA] [-l N] [--build BUILD] [-g [FIELD [FIELD ...]]] [--order_by [FIELD [FIELD ...]]] [-u] [-v {0,1,2}] from_table [condition [condition ...]] Exclude variants according to properties (variant and annotation fields) and membership (samples) of variant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meta_analysis</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/meta_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/meta_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Meta-analysis for Association Testing Results Introduction vtools_report meta_analysis implements meta-analysis methods detailed in Willer et al 2010[^C. J. Willer, Y. Li and G. R. Abecasis (2010). METAL: fast and efficient meta-analysis of genomewide association scans. Bioinformatics^]. Two statistics are available: the sample size based statistic and inverse variance based statistic. Input of this command are multiple text or compressed text files of association results delimited by tabs.
Details Command interface % vtools_report meta_analysis -h usage: vtools_report meta_analysis [-h] [--beta col] [--pval col] [--se col] [-n col] [--link col [col .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>compare</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/compare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/compare/</guid>
      <description>Compare two or more variant tables 1. Usage % vtools compare -h usage: vtools compare [-h] [--union [TABLE [DESC ...]]] [--intersection [TABLE [DESC ...]]] [--difference [TABLE [DESC ...]]] [--expression EXPR [DESC ...]] [--mode {variant,site,genotype}] [--samples [SAMPLES [SAMPLES ...]]] [-v {0,1,2}] [tables [tables ...]] Get the difference, intersection and union of two or more variant tables, according to sites, variants, or genotypes of associated samples of these variants. Resulting variants can be counted or write to other variant tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plot_fields</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/plot_fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/plot_fields/</guid>
      <description>Plot fields from variant tables Usage % vtools_report plot_fields -h usage: vtools_report plot_fields [-h] [--variants TABLE] [--save_data FILENAME] [--save_script FILENAME] [--width px] [--height px] [--hist name] [--norm_curve] [--dot name] [--dot_size pt] [--discrete_color {Dark2,grayscale,default,BrBG,PiYG,PRGn,PuOr,RdBu,RdGy,RdYlBu,RdYlGn,Spectral,Accent,Paired,Pastel1,Pastel2,Set1,Set2,Set3,Blues,BuGn,BuPu,GnBu,Greens,Greys,Oranges,OrRd,PuBu,PuBuGn,PuRd,Purples,RdPu,Reds,YlGn,YlGnBu,YlOrBr,YlOrRd}] [--box name] [--stratify C [C ...]] [--outlier_size pt] [--color {Dark2,grayscale,default,BrBG,PiYG,PRGn,PuOr,RdBu,RdGy,RdYlBu,RdYlGn,Spectral,Accent,Paired,Pastel1,Pastel2,Set1,Set2,Set3,Blues,BuGn,BuPu,GnBu,Greens,Greys,Oranges,OrRd,PuBu,PuBuGn,PuRd,Purples,RdPu,Reds,YlGn,YlGnBu,YlOrBr,YlOrRd}] [-v {0,1,2}] fields [fields ...] positional arguments: fields A list of fields that will be outputted. optional arguments: -h, --help show this help message and exit --variants TABLE Limit value of fields to variant in specified variant table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>associate</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/associate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/associate/</guid>
      <description>Identify genotype - phenotype association 1. Usage % vtools associate -h usage: vtools associate [-h] [--covariates [COVARIATES [COVARIATES ...]]] [--var_info [VAR_INFO [VAR_INFO ...]]] [--geno_info [GENO_INFO [GENO_INFO ...]]] [-m METHODS [METHODS ...]] [-g [GROUP_BY [GROUP_BY ...]]] [-s [COND [COND ...]]] [--genotypes [COND [COND ...]]] [--discard_samples [EXPR [EXPR ...]]] [--discard_variants [EXPR [EXPR ...]]] [--to_db annoDB] [-f] [-j N] [-v {0,1,2}] variants phenotypes Call one or more statistical association tests and return test results as fields to variants tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plot_geno_fields</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/plot_geno_fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/plot_geno_fields/</guid>
      <description>Plot genotype and/or genotype information fields Usage % vtools_report plot_geno_fields -h usage: vtools_report plot_geno_fields [-h] [--variants TABLE] [--samples [SAMPLES [SAMPLES ...]]] [--genotypes [GENOTYPES [GENOTYPES ...]]] [--save_data FILENAME] [--save_script FILENAME] [--width px] [--height px] [--hist name] [--norm_curve] [--dot name] [--dot_size pt] [--discrete_color {Dark2,grayscale,default,BrBG,PiYG,PRGn,PuOr,RdBu,RdGy,RdYlBu,RdYlGn,Spectral,Accent,Paired,Pastel1,Pastel2,Set1,Set2,Set3,Blues,BuGn,BuPu,GnBu,Greens,Greys,Oranges,OrRd,PuBu,PuBuGn,PuRd,Purples,RdPu,Reds,YlGn,YlGnBu,YlOrBr,YlOrRd}] [--box name] [--stratify C [C ...]] [--outlier_size pt] [--color {Dark2,grayscale,default,BrBG,PiYG,PRGn,PuOr,RdBu,RdGy,RdYlBu,RdYlGn,Spectral,Accent,Paired,Pastel1,Pastel2,Set1,Set2,Set3,Blues,BuGn,BuPu,GnBu,Greens,Greys,Oranges,OrRd,PuBu,PuBuGn,PuRd,Purples,RdPu,Reds,YlGn,YlGnBu,YlOrBr,YlOrRd}] [-v {0,1,2}] fields [fields ...] positional arguments: fields A list of genotype fields that will be outputted. optional arguments: -h, --help show this help message and exit --variants TABLE Limit value of fields to variant in specified variant table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>output</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/output/</guid>
      <description>Output variants in a variant table 1. Usage % vtools output -h usage: vtools output [-h] [--header [HEADER [HEADER ...]]] [-d DELIMITER] [--na NA] [-l N] [--build BUILD] [-g [FIELD [FIELD ...]]] [--all] [--order_by FIELD [FIELD ...]] [-v {0,1,2}] table fields [fields ...] Output variants, variant info fields, annotation fields and expressions that involve these fields in a tab or comma separated format. positional arguments: table variants to output. fields A list of fields that will be outputted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plot_pheno_fields</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/plot_pheno_fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/plot_pheno_fields/</guid>
      <description>Plot Sample phenotype fields Usage % vtools_report plot_pheno_fields -h usage: vtools_report plot_pheno_fields [-h] [--samples [SAMPLES [SAMPLES ...]]] [--save_data FILENAME] [--save_script FILENAME] [--width px] [--height px] [--hist name] [--norm_curve] [--dot name] [--dot_size pt] [--discrete_color {Dark2,grayscale,default,BrBG,PiYG,PRGn,PuOr,RdBu,RdGy,RdYlBu,RdYlGn,Spectral,Accent,Paired,Pastel1,Pastel2,Set1,Set2,Set3,Blues,BuGn,BuPu,GnBu,Greens,Greys,Oranges,OrRd,PuBu,PuBuGn,PuRd,Purples,RdPu,Reds,YlGn,YlGnBu,YlOrBr,YlOrRd}] [--box name] [--stratify C [C ...]] [--outlier_size pt] [--color {Dark2,grayscale,default,BrBG,PiYG,PRGn,PuOr,RdBu,RdGy,RdYlBu,RdYlGn,Spectral,Accent,Paired,Pastel1,Pastel2,Set1,Set2,Set3,Blues,BuGn,BuPu,GnBu,Greens,Greys,Oranges,OrRd,PuBu,PuBuGn,PuRd,Purples,RdPu,Reds,YlGn,YlGnBu,YlOrBr,YlOrRd}] [-v {0,1,2}] fields [fields ...] positional arguments: fields A list of fields that will be outputted. optional arguments: -h, --help show this help message and exit --samples [SAMPLES [SAMPLES .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>export</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/export/</guid>
      <description>Export variants and samples to external files 1. Usage % vtools export -h usage: vtools export [-h] [-o [OUTPUT]] [-s [COND [COND ...]]] [--format FORMAT] [--build BUILD] [--header [HEADER [HEADER ...]]] [-j JOBS] [-v {0,1,2}] table Export variants and genotypes in text, vcf and other formats. positional arguments: table A variant table whose variants will be exported. If parameter --samples is specified, only variants belong to one or more of the samples will be exported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plot_association</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/plot_association/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools_report/plot_association/</guid>
      <description>Graphic Summary of Association Analysis Introduction vtools_report plot_association generates QQ plot and Manhattan plot of p-values from output of vtools associate command. The graphics are powered by the R package ggplot2. Fonts, color, page layout etc can be specified from the command interface, generating high quality and customized graphs.
Input data format vtools associate command typically generates two types of output: output of gene based association tests and single variant analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>remove</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/remove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/remove/</guid>
      <description>Remove project, variant table, fields and others 1. Usage % vtools remove -h usage: vtools remove [-h] [-v STD[LOG]] {project,tables,samples,fields,geno_fields,annotations,variants,genotypes,phenotypes} [items [items ...]] Remove from the current project various items such as variants genotypes, and annotation fields. positional arguments: {project,tables,samples,fields,geno_fields,annotations,variants,genotypes,phenotypes} Type of items to be removed. items Items to be removed, which should be, for &#39;project&#39; the name of project to be removed (optional), for &#39;tables&#39; names of one or more variant tables, for &#39;samples&#39; patterns using which matching samples are removed, for &#39;fields&#39; name of fields to be removed, for &#39;geno_fields&#39; name of genotype fields to be removed (cf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>execute</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/execute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/execute/</guid>
      <description>Execute variant tools pipelines 1. Usage % vtools execute -h usage: vtools execute [-h] [-i [INPUT_FILE [INPUT_FILE ...]]] [-o [OUTPUT_FILE [OUTPUT_FILE ...]]] [-j JOBS] [-d DELIMITER] [-v {0,1,2}] PIPELINE/QUERY [PIPELINE/QUERY ...] Execute a pipeline that uses external commands to process input files, usually to align raw reads to a reference genome and call variants from aligned reads. The pipelines are controlled by pipeline description files. This command can also be used to execute arbitrary SQL query against the project database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>admin</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/vtools-commands/admin/</guid>
      <description>Miscellaneous administrative procedures 1. Usage % vtools admin -h usage: vtools admin [-h] [--update_resource [TYPE]] [--mirror_repository dest] [--merge_samples] [--rename_samples COND [COND ...]] [--rename_table NAME NEW_NAME] [--describe_table TABLE NEW_DESCRIPTION] [--validate_build] [--validate_sex] [--save_snapshot NAME MESSAGE] [--extra_files [FILE [FILE ...]]] [--load_snapshot NAME] [--set_runtime_option OPTION [OPTION ...]] [--reset_runtime_option OPT] [--fasta2crr FASTA [FASTA ...]] [-v {0,1,2,3}] Optimize or modify projects. Currently supports merging and rename of samples optional arguments: -h, --help show this help message and exit -v {0,1,2,3}, --verbosity {0,1,2,3} Output error and warning (0), info (1), debug (2) and trace (3) information to standard output (default to 1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/use-__-variant-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/use-__-variant-tools/</guid>
      <description>use :: Variant Tools  :root #header + #content  #left  #rlblock_left{ display:none !important; } :not(pre)  code + span.copy-to-clipboard { display: none; }            var baseurl = &#39;\/vat-docs\/&#39;;    Installation   Documentation   Key concepts   Supported types of variants     Tutorials   Help   Vtools commands   Init   Import   Update   Phenotype   lifttover   show   use   use   select   exclude   compare   associate   output   export   remove   execute   admin     Functions   ref_sequence   mut_sequence   track   Genotype   samples   in_table   Other functions     Vtools_report   avg_depth   discordance_rate   sam_info   sequence   trans_ratio   variant_stat   inbreeding_coefficient   transmission   meta_analysis   plot_fields   plot_geno_fields   plot_pheno_fields   plot_association     Customization   Simulation   Introduction   Customized simulations   Models   Peng2014_ex1   Peng2014_ex2       Format   Formats   basic   csv   plink   rsname   Cumtomized   tped   map         Pipelines   Introduction   Customized pipeline   Variant calling   bwa_gatk33_hg19   bat_gatk33_b37   bwa_gatk28_hg19   bwa_gatk28_b37     Other pipelines   import_vcf   anno_utils   transmission   Illumnina   ANNOVAR   snpEff   KING       Utilities   report_progress   md5sumd       Application   Annotation   Introduction   Tutorial   Customized annotation databases   Genes   ccdsGene   Hugo gene   EntrezGene   knownGene   refGene   CancerGeneCensus     Variants   COSMIC   sbNSFP   dbSNP   linkage-physical map   Database of Genomic Variants   Exome Sequencing Project   gwasCatalog   HapMap   Thousand Genomes     Regions   Low complexity regions   Phast cons   Genomic super dups   cytoBand     Misc   Illumina   keggPathway   ENCODE       Discovery   Association   Introduction   Data exploration/QC   Association analysis   Post-assoc analysis   Basic data statistics   Group stat&amp;amp;Write     Single variant analysis   Fisher exact test     Single gene association methods   Introduction   CMC test   C-alpha test   KBAC test   RBT test   RareCover test   VT test   WSS test   aSum test     Joint/Conditional association analysis   Collapsing methods   Aggregation methods   Weighted methods   Variable thresholds   SKAT test   MetaSKAT analysis     VAT stacking   Create your test!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/use-__-variant-tools_files/saved_resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/use-__-variant-tools_files/saved_resource/</guid>
      <description>@import &#34;chrome-extension://hfapbcheiepjppjbnkphkmegjlipojba/css/style.css&#34;  Piggy&#39;s Asleep What happened to the pig who lost its voice? It became disgruntled!
  This website doesn&#39;t work with us.
Piggy has temporarily deactivated itself, but we&#39;re ready to save you money the next time you visit a website that works with Piggy.
localhost
Request to Add This Site Report a problem  Thanks for your input!
We&#39;ve added this to the list and will try to get our engineers on it ASAP!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/_footer/</guid>
      <description>copyright = &amp;copy; Bo Peng, Ph.D. / MD AndersonCancer Center All rights reserved</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/under-development/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/under-development/faq/</guid>
      <description>Import data Some of my samples occur in multiple vcf files but their genotype calls may be different. How can I identify them after they are imported? Because a file might contain genotype for multiple samples (.vcf), and genotype for a sample can be spread into several files (your case), a sample in variant tools is uniquely identified by filename and sample_name in the output of &amp;ldquo;vtools show sample&amp;rdquo;. However</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>