<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Formats on Variant Tools</title>
    <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Formats on Variant Tools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>basic</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/txt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/txt/</guid>
      <description>Importing variants from tab-delimited files Format description % vtools show format basic A basic variant import/export format that import variants with four tab- delimited columns (chr, pos, ref, alt), and export variants, optional variant info fields and genotypes. Columns: 1 Output variant info fields as one column 2 variant position, set --pos_adj to -1 to export variants in 0-based positions. 3 reference allele 4 alternative allele 5 genotype in numeric style Formatters are provided for fields: gt variant: chr Chromosome pos 1-based position, set --pos_adj to 1 if input position is 0 based.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>csv</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/csv/</guid>
      <description>Importing and exporting variants in .csv (comma-separated value) format Format description When this format is used to import data, it is similar to the basic? format except that it assumes the use of commas, instead of tabs, as delimiters of the input format.
When this format is used to export variants, it can be used to export arbitrary fields. The command and the resulting ouput are similar to that of the command vtools output --delimiter , (output fields with a delimiter of comma), except that the vtools export --format csv command will properly quote field values when it contains comma, quotation mark etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plink</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/plink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/plink/</guid>
      <description>Import variants and sample genotypes from PLINK format Introduction PLINK is a widely used program for analyzing genotypic data for Genome-wide Association Studies (GWAS). It can be considered as standard input format for genotyping array data. An intermediate type of genetic data between genotyping arrays and exome sequencing is the exome genotyping array, or exome chip. Unlike its GWAS counterpart which focuses on relatively common variants, exome chips contain primarily non-singleton coding variants seen in existing whole genome and exome sequencing data, plus a small proportion of non-protein-altering variants such as GWAS tag SNPs, ancestry informative markers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rsname</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/rsname/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/rsname/</guid>
      <description>Importing variants from a list of dbSNP iDs (rsnames) Format description % vtools show format rsname Import variants (chr, pos, ref, alt) that are queried from dbSNP database using provided rsnames Columns: None defined, cannot export to this format variant: chr Obtain chromosome from dbSNP by rsname pos Obtain position from dbSNP by rsname ref Obtain reference allele from dbSNP by rsname alt Obtain alternative allele from dbSNP by rsname Format parameters: sep delimiter used to separate input fields (default: &#39;,&#39;) rsname_col Index for the column with rsname (default: 1) dbfile Name of an attached dbSNP database or path to the dbSNP database in sqlite format (default: dbSNP- hg19_138.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cumtomized</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/new/</guid>
      <description>Specification of external file formats Roles of format specification in variant tools: Variant tools can import and export text files (or gzipped text files) in delimiter-separated format, namely records that are separated into columns by delimiters such as tab, space or comma. The file format must be variant-oriented (storing one or more variants by line), with the exception of sample-based PLINK format which is preprocessed internally into variant-oriented form for import.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tped</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/tped/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/tped/</guid>
      <description>PLINK/TPED format About TPED format Many software applications for linkage and association studies (e.g. plink, merlin) accept PED/MAP format. The map file records basic information about markers, the Ped file contains sample genotype. Whereas variant tools can easily export in MAP format, it is difficult to export in PED format because this format is not variant oriented (output by variant).
Fortunately, PLINK accepts a transposed PED format (TPED) that is variant oriented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>map</title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/map/</guid>
      <description>Import variants from file without ref and alt alleles Introduction From time to time, you might get a list of variants in map format, or as a list with only chromosome and position information. Reference and alternative alleles are not specified because the variants are from GWA studies with well-defined reference and alternative alleles. In this case, you can use format map, which automatically retrieve reference and alternative alleles from a specified dbSNP database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/use-__-variant-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/use-__-variant-tools/</guid>
      <description>use :: Variant Tools  :root #header + #content  #left  #rlblock_left{ display:none !important; } :not(pre)  code + span.copy-to-clipboard { display: none; }            var baseurl = &#39;\/vat-docs\/&#39;;    Installation   Documentation   Key concepts   Supported types of variants     Tutorials   Help   Vtools commands   Init   Import   Update   Phenotype   lifttover   show   use   use   select   exclude   compare   associate   output   export   remove   execute   admin     Functions   ref_sequence   mut_sequence   track   Genotype   samples   in_table   Other functions     Vtools_report   avg_depth   discordance_rate   sam_info   sequence   trans_ratio   variant_stat   inbreeding_coefficient   transmission   meta_analysis   plot_fields   plot_geno_fields   plot_pheno_fields   plot_association     Customization   Simulation   Introduction   Customized simulations   Models   Peng2014_ex1   Peng2014_ex2       Format   Formats   basic   csv   plink   rsname   Cumtomized   tped   map         Pipelines   Introduction   Customized pipeline   Variant calling   bwa_gatk33_hg19   bat_gatk33_b37   bwa_gatk28_hg19   bwa_gatk28_b37     Other pipelines   import_vcf   anno_utils   transmission   Illumnina   ANNOVAR   snpEff   KING       Utilities   report_progress   md5sumd       Application   Annotation   Introduction   Tutorial   Customized annotation databases   Genes   ccdsGene   Hugo gene   EntrezGene   knownGene   refGene   CancerGeneCensus     Variants   COSMIC   sbNSFP   dbSNP   linkage-physical map   Database of Genomic Variants   Exome Sequencing Project   gwasCatalog   HapMap   Thousand Genomes     Regions   Low complexity regions   Phast cons   Genomic super dups   cytoBand     Misc   Illumina   keggPathway   ENCODE       Discovery   Association   Introduction   Data exploration/QC   Association analysis   Post-assoc analysis   Basic data statistics   Group stat&amp;amp;Write     Single variant analysis   Fisher exact test     Single gene association methods   Introduction   CMC test   C-alpha test   KBAC test   RBT test   RareCover test   VT test   WSS test   aSum test     Joint/Conditional association analysis   Collapsing methods   Aggregation methods   Weighted methods   Variable thresholds   SKAT test   MetaSKAT analysis     VAT stacking   Create your test!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/use-__-variant-tools_files/saved_resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatlab.github.io/vat-docs/documentation/customization/format/formats/use-__-variant-tools_files/saved_resource/</guid>
      <description>@import &#34;chrome-extension://hfapbcheiepjppjbnkphkmegjlipojba/css/style.css&#34;  Piggy&#39;s Asleep What happened to the pig who lost its voice? It became disgruntled!
  This website doesn&#39;t work with us.
Piggy has temporarily deactivated itself, but we&#39;re ready to save you money the next time you visit a website that works with Piggy.
localhost
Request to Add This Site Report a problem  Thanks for your input!
We&#39;ve added this to the list and will try to get our engineers on it ASAP!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>